Luis Herrera

Building our present.

Cali, Valle del Cauca 1209@holbertonschool.com +573057128788

Cryptocurrency privacy-focused Monero (XMR) enthusiast. Focused in open-source sofware GNU/Linux operating systems since 2016.

Studied Sofware Engineering foundations at Holberton School Colombia with a high passion for blockchain technology.

Entrepreneur, adventurer, and eager to develop code for our world.

Experience in C, Python, and JavaScript programming languages, hand-coded HTML and CSS with MySQL database integration.

Work Experience

Communication Group Coordinator (Volunteer)

Monero

July 2018 to Present

Workgroup production coordinator. Organize translators, transcriptionist's workload and publish final content throughout the community.

Software Engineer

Holberton School - Cali September 2019 to June 2020

Full-time programmer. Experience with C, Python, and Javascript programming languages, and database management with MySQL (SQLalchemy).

During this project, we developed 3 low-level C programming & algorithms projects, 4 higher level Python and

JavaScript programming projects, 8 system engineering DevOps projects, a Social Media build profile, and our own portfolio project that was live transmitted through Facebook live. We also used MySQL as relational database management systems, SQLalchemy, RESTful, and JavaScript APIs and deployed virtual servers using

Docker and hardware servers.

Database Analyst

EMCALI - Cali, Valle del Cauca September 2016 to February 2018

Database analyst. I also did the Geographic Information System software (GEOVISOR/MapInfo) colleagues training. My main task was to maintain the database information updated using the integrated OPEN-

Smart Flex software. Databases were handled using Microsoft Excel crossed-based between different government official databases (FOSYGA, RUAF, DIAN, and PROCURADURIA).

Business Development Administrator

Productos Vrinda

February 2013 to May 2016

Production and service manager. My responsibilities were to cover the customer service area, staff planning, purchase, storage, and sales. I had to contact suppliers, make the financial accounting control, have resource optimization, and comply with quality standards and regulations of the food and beverage sector.

Geo referencer

Collector

Servinformación - Cali, Valle del Cauca February 2010 to February 2013

Feb 2010 - Feb 2013 (3 years 1 month)

Homologue national property number in the company's databases to the EMCALI subscriber. I also made routing fieldwork through Geographic Information Systems (GIS). Geographic software layer control, collector supervisor, and location coordinates updates. Software: MapInfo, Excel, Access.

Commercial Director

Chef en tu Casa - Cali 2012 to 2012

2012 (1 year)

Logistics, purchases, accounting, and cash management.

CSR

Kimeline

December 2010 to March 2011

Customer Service Representative

Education

School in Software Engineering

Holberton School - Cali

September 2019 to June 2020

Certificate in Web development

Udemy Academy - Cali

September 2017 to March 2018

Skills

- English
- · Customer Service
- Team Leadership
- MapInfo Professional

- C (Programming Language)
- Python (Programming Language)
- JavaScript
- MySQL
- Programming
- Open Source Software
- HTML5
- APIs
- CSS
- Git
- REST

Links

http://linkedin.com/in/lh1008

https://github.com/lh1008